<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Diving With the Whale - Docker Series on Ahmed Ayman</title>
    <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diving With the Whale - Docker Series on Ahmed Ayman</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://a7medayman6.github.io/static/</url>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/static/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 01:21:21 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro &amp; Installation</title>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 14:50:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-i/</guid>
      <description>Diving with the Whale - Docker Day I - Intro &amp;amp; Installation Author : Ahmed Ayman
 &amp;ldquo;Believe it or not, Evergreen vs. the Suez Canal was NOT the biggest container event of the year. #DockerCon is!&amp;rdquo;
  Docker official page on Facebook.  Containers Overview What are Containers ? Containers, in short, contain applications in a way that keep them isolated from the host system that they run on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Containers &amp; Images Management</title>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 15:53:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-ii/</guid>
      <description>Diving with the Whale - Docker Day II - Containers &amp;amp; Images Management Author : Ahmed Ayman
Stuff You Should know  ONLY ONE!  Docker containers are designed to run only one process.   Ephemeral (lasting for a very short time)  Docker containers are meant to be ephemeral, once their process completes the container goes to sleep, and it&amp;rsquo;s memories about anything happened while it was running goes with it !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persisting Data &amp; Docker Files</title>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:34:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-iii/</guid>
      <description>Diving with the Whale - Docker Day III - Persisting Data &amp;amp; Docker Files Author : Ahmed Ayman
Remember when I said No persisting data with a really bold font? well I lied ! 😅 Persisting Data Containers are designed to be ephemeral and isolated from the host machine. This creates problems when data is involved.
BUT, There is two ways around it actually
1. Mapping Volumes Just the same as we mapped ports we can map directories from the host machine to a container directory, so anything happens here happens there and vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Networking, Entry Points, and more.</title>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-iv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 01:16:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-iv/</guid>
      <description>Diving with the Whale - Docker Day IV - Docker Networking, Entry Points, and more. Docker Networking How can we let two or more containers talking to each other ? through docker containers!
Networking in containers is controlling who can talk to who including all the running containers, and the local-host.
  Docker Network Drivers
Several drivers exist by default in docker, and provide core networking functionality
  Bridge Network</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker Compose and Multi-Container Apps</title>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-v/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 01:21:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a7medayman6.github.io/blog/devops/diving-with-the-whale-docker-series/day-v/</guid>
      <description>Diving with the Whale - Docker Day V - Docker Compose and Multi-Container Apps Author : Ahmed Ayman
Container Orchestration Container orchestration is the automatic process of managing or scheduling the work of individual containers for applications based on micro-services within multiple clusters. The widely deployed container orchestration platforms are based on open-source versions like Kubernetes, Docker Swarm or the commercial version from Red Hat Open-shift.
If you want to manage tens, hundreds, or even thousands of containers, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that manually of course !</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
