<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Stuff Spining In My Head on Ahmed Ayman</title>
    <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stuff Spining In My Head on Ahmed Ayman</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://a7medayman6.github.io/static/</url>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/static/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 02:28:16 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://a7medayman6.github.io/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LIFE IS DETERMINISTIC, HMMMM, OR NOT.</title>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/thoughts/determinism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a7medayman6.github.io/thoughts/determinism/</guid>
      <description>If someday, somehow we managed to see the future, that means the future is deterministic. It means that every thing that will ever happen is predetermined; because if we can see it or predict it with some technology then it’s already there, and our choices have been already made! We just had to observe it. Let’s just assume for a minute that we’re okay with living without free-will. But now when we know exactly what’s gonna happen after say five seconds from now, you can change it right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>عشوائيات</title>
      <link>https://a7medayman6.github.io/thoughts/randoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 02:28:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://a7medayman6.github.io/thoughts/randoms/</guid>
      <description>1  الفراغ قاتل، الملل قد يبدأ سلسلة جرائم قتل، الانتحار وسيلة، النوم هروب، الاحلام افكار، الكوابيس مخاوف مختبئة، العقل ألم، الجنون عدم توقع، الموت حقيقة حتميه، الطريق اختيار، الألم نبضات، التنفس استمرار، القتل لذة، الجحيم دولة، الحب وشم في الذاكرة، القوة كذبة، الأصدقاء أوقات، الجنس قيود متحررة، القهوة ذكرى، الشيكولاتة انتحار، المباني سجون، التكنولوجيا مخرج، الجهل عله، المعرفة عبئ، التدخين فيلم سئ.  2  الفكرة شريط لاصق، الظلام راحة أبديه، اللقاءات ارتياح، الهجر مسافات، العلاقات عذاب مفروض، العزلة استحالة، التقاطع وجوب، الموسيقى مهدئ، فقدان الذاكرة رصاصة رحمة، الليل جمال، الأسود رقي، الإنتشاء أدرينالين، الروايات حياه مختبئة بين السطور، المرض خطة، السجن يذهب العقل، الشرفات سور يطل على الاحلام، العيون مشاعر.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
